Sergiy Safronov

Contact

sergiy.safronov@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sergiy-safronov-45324210 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

C++ MySQL Python PHP AWS Docker

Core competencies

Full stack development API design Cloud-based deployment Managing large data volumes

Summary

Senior Software Developer with 12+ years experience in the design, development and delivery of robust code for distributed systems handling millions of transactions on a daily basis. Delivered integrations to the REST APIs of over 20 financial services for MNOs across a globe. Confident, great attention to detail with experience in full-stack software development mainly with C++, MySOL and PHP.

Technical Expertise

Languages: C++, Python, PHP, Javascript&JQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Methodologies: Scrum and Kanban (working with Jira)

Database: MySQL, DynamoDB

Testing/Continuous Integration: GitLab, Jenkins driving Docker builds

and running tests

OS: Linux (CentOS, Debian, Ubuntu)

Cloud Service: AWS (RDS, EC2, Beanstalk, Lambda, CloudFormation) **Misc Skills:** Haproxy, Apache, Bootstrap, RegEx, Git, Boost, Django **APIs:** Restful API Design using Swagger/OpenAPI, SOAP, JSON, XML

Requirements: GDPR, OWASP

Monitoring: Prometheus/Grafana, Zabbix

Professional experience

Tola Mobile

Senior Software Developer August 2015 – Present Dublin

Tola is a mobile payment service provider. Taking the hassle, cost and risk out of paying for goods and services by allowing consumers to pay directly from their mobile, charging transactions to a mobile wallet or phone account.

The model adds value to all parties in the ecosystem – merchant, MNO and consumer.

The technology stack includes a horizontally scalable distributed system which connects with hundreds of partners and delivers millions of financial transactions per day.

Areas of expertise include:

- Developing bespoke back-end and front-end solutions using modern software development techniques across various market sectors including Telecommunications and Finance.
- Using Agile Scrum Methodology throughout the code development phases.
- Developing secure code which adheres to data protection rules.
- Understanding and prioritising tasks; estimating development time and refining large features into smaller bodies of work.
- Developing object oriented, multi-threaded code which is both maintainable and scalable.

- · Lead Engineer in designing APIs
- Working knowledge of Cloud-based deployment architectures
- Defining metrics which can be used to monitor the live status of the platform.
- Coordinating with the engineering and product teams to identify the customer requirements for new products.
- Collaborating with the product management and architecture teams to development scalable integrations to external companies for our applications.

ECOsyNRG

Senior Software Developer 2012 - August 2015 (3 years 8 months) Dublin

- Provide solutions to win in ESB/ SBIR/ NI DRD tenders and passed requirements to get Enterprise Ireland grant.
- Led the development of software stack for Charging Station Management System (CSMS) including implementation OCPP protocol (XML and JSON versions).
- Integrated with existing Payment and Billing reconciliation Systems.
- Research and test platform to implement Vehicle-to-Grid (ISO 15118).

M2C Wireless Machine

Software Developer September 2010 - September 2012 (2 years 1 month) Dublin

- Managing development team / advise students in university's projects.
- Software design, coding and verification (C/C++, embedded C, PHP).
- Setup and maintained database environment Apache, MySQL and PHP.
- Monitor system and component, maintenance tasks, and reporting systems as needed.

Euroformat

C/C++ Programmer 2006 - 2010 (5 years) Ukraine

- Developing software in C/C++ in request of company departments.
- Provide interdepartmental technical support as required.
- Preparing and writing training manuals for users.

Education

Kiev National University, 2001-2006

Complete Higher Education with the speciality of

Automated Management of Technological Processes

and acquired the qualification of **Automation Engineer**.

Awarded: Bachelor's in Automation. 2001-2005

Awarded: Master's Degree Diploma with Honours. 2005-2006

Diplomas are recognized in Qualification Recognition of Ireland (Level 9 of NFQ).